Register of the Vitalii Ivanovich Petropavlovskii Papers, 1917-1933
Hoover Institution Archives
Vitalii Ivanovich Petropavlovskii Papers,
1917-1933
99051
Petropavlovskii, Vitalii Ivanovich
2 microfilm reels (0.3 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, reports, financial records, and printed matter, relating to relations of the Russian Provisional and White Russian governments with the United States during the Russian Revolution and Civil War.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1999
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Location of Originals
Originals in: Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco.
Access Points
Soviet Union--History--Revolution, 1917-1921.; Soviet Union--History--Allied intervention, 1918-1920.; Russia--Foreign relations--United States.; United States--Foreign relations--Russia.; Russia.; Soviet Union.; United States--Foreign relations.
Biography
Russian government purchasing agent in the United States, 1917-1921
Biographical Note
? Born, Russia
? Engineering degree
1912 Enters government service as official of Russian State Control
1916 Chief Auditor, Department of Railway Accounting, Russian State Control
1917 Appointed Representative of Russian State Control, U.S.A.
1921 Retired with liquidation of Russian State Control Office
Scope and Content
This collection consists of materials relating to financial reviews of the activities of the Russkii zagotovitel'nyi komitet (Russian Purchasing Committee) and other official Russian financial and purchasing agencies in the U.S.A., as well as of reports of the activities of the Control office, correspondence with Ambassador B. A. Bakhmeteff, Financial Agent S. A. Ughet, as well as with direct superiors and subordinates in the Russian State Control.
The collection also deals with general Russian financial issues and allegations of financial improprieties among Russian officials and commissions.
Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and Museum of Russian Culture. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials and copyright to them (with some exceptions) are the property of the Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is available at the Hoover Institution Archives.
The Hoover Institution assumes all responsibility for notifying users that they must comply with the copyright law of the United States (Title 17 United States Code) and Hoover Rules for the Use and Reproduction of Archival Materials.
Series Description
- OFFICE FILE, 1917-1933., Box 1
  Correspondence, reports, instructions, directives, financial documents and registers, clippings and other printed matter. The original arrangement of this collection into numerical files by Petropavlovskii has been preserved, but material within the files has been described in greater detail
- MISCELLANY, 1918., Box 1
  One book
Container List
- Office File, 1917-1933
  - File 1. "Sobstvennoe delo po sluzhbe v S.-A.S.Sh. V. I. Petropavlovskogo." Official correspondence with Russian Ambassador B. A. Bakhmeteff, Financial Agent in the U.S., S. A. Ughet, his assistant, D. P. Pertsov, Petropavlovskii's subordinate, V. I. Zbyshevskii, and others; certificates, clippings and other papers relating to Petropavlovskii's appointment in June 1917, including certificate signed by Secretary of State Robert Lansing recognizing his authority, 1918 November 1. Also includes reports to and correspondence with superiors in Petrograd (M. I. Skipetrov) and Omsk (G. Krasnov), list of employees of the Russian State Control Office in the U.S.A., with group photograph, correspondence, financial reports and other documents relating to the closing of the Office and liquidation of its affairs in 1921 (Box 1., Folder 1)
  - File 2. "Svedeniia o deiatel'nosti gosudarstvennogo kontrolia v S. A. S. Sh." Official reports of the activities of the State Control Office, with supporting documentation and correspondence (Folder 2)
  - File 3. "Sobranie zakonopolozhenii, rasporiazhenii, pravil, instruktsii i proektov, kasaiushchikhsia Gosudarstvennogo Kontrolia, a takzhe polozhenii ob uchrezhdeniiakh zagotovitel'nogo i torgovogo naznacheniia." Compilation of laws, instructions, orders and rules governing the activities of the State Control Office as well as of official purchasing and trade commissions (Folder 3)
  - File 4. "Raznye doklady i dublikaty." Includes correspondence with B. A. Bakhmeteff, S. A. Ughet, and others, minutes of meetings of the Russkii zagotovitel'nyi komitet, 1917-1918, official rules and regulations governing the work of various Russian governmental organizations, and documents relating to the fate of the archive and materials of the Office of Russian State Control in the U.S.A. (Folder 4)
  - File 5. "Raznye materialy po Ross. Gosud. Kontroliu v Sev. Amer. Soed. Sht." Includes brochure by D. G. Ter-Asaturov, Dopolnitel'naia zapiska o deiatel'nosti rossiiskogo predstavitel'stva v Amerike (Pictou, N.S., Canada, 1925) and typewritten answers of M. M. Karpovich and D. P. Pertsov to the author's earlier accusations of financial improprieties, as well as correspondence between Ughet and Petropavlovskii relating to same. Also includes typescript by W. J. Novitsky, "Russian Gold Reserve" (Folder 5)
- Miscellany, 1918.
  - One book by M. I. Gaiduk, entitled Utiug (New York, 1918) (Box 1., Folder 6)